Hi, I'm Finian Joyce, chief fire officer from Leitrim in
Ireland. This new campaign, called European Smoke Alarm
Day, is a very welcome addition to the activities of
European Fire Safety Week.
It's great to see the collaboration on this campaign
between the European Fire Safety Alliance and the
Federation of European Fire Officers.
I am aware that many services around Europe organise
campaigns individually in their own countries to promote
the installation of smoke alarms,
but this is the first time that European fire services have
come together to promote greater awareness about smoke
alarms. For many years we here in Ireland have regulations
in place in relation to smoke alarms in domestic homes,
and no doubt this has helped to save many lives.
I'm delighted to offer the support of the Irish Chief Fire
Officers for this new European campaign,
and would like to see more countries in Europe making it
mandatory to install smoke alarms in domestic homes.
My final message to householders is to say that this little
piece of equipment can make a real difference in your lives.
Install smoke alarms in your homes today.